

# Prajakta Dharmadhikari

Corporate HR | L&D Professional | HRMS

A proactive and fast learning individual, thirst to learn and explore with enthusiastic and professional approach. Equipped with the required skill set in L & D, training facilitation & Communication & Corporate HR activities. Experience in creating & Leading training & development programs.

prajaktadlinkedin@gmail.com



8446044038



Pune, India



in linkedin.com/in/prajakta-dharmadhikari

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

### Trainer - L & D

PD's Academy (Self-Employed & Freelancer)

02/2015 - Present

Pune, India

Achievements/Tasks

- Customized Curriculum Development, One-on-One Instruction and Guidance, Student Progress Assessment and Feedback, Parent and Guardian Collaboration.
- Acquired, Arranged & developed training process manuals, guidelines & course materials such as handouts & visuals for GD & PI for PG M.B.A. Students. Increased participants engagement by 30%.
- Enrichment and Supplemental Learning Activities. Examined different training delivery methods such as in-person & virtual to improve training efficiency, costs or environmental consequences.
- Problem Solving, Educational Leadership, Leadership, Teaching. Designed trainings & peer-mentoring programs.
- Facilitated onboarding and soft-skills training programs.
- Managed all training logistics, vendor coordination and posttraining evaluations.

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

## Freelance Trainer

IDEA Foundation (NGO)

Tasks/Achievements

- Trained the staff through various activities (like drama, role-play), Conducted Critical thinking & Design Thinking training for staff, Taught Math & English to the high-school students.

## **KEY SKILLS & COMPETENCIES**

## Technical Skills/Corporate Training & Facilitation

wide experience in Education domain. Skilled in corporate training & facilitation using new age methodologies to drive engagement, participation & measurable outcomes. (Freelance)

#### **Employee Engagement & Retention**

Drove employee well-being programs, reward & recognition frameworks, and cultural initiatives at the shop floor in Eaton fluid power Limited during my Internship period.

## Training Needs Analysis (TNA)

Identifying training needs within an organization.

#### Curriculum Development, LMS, Evaluation & Feedback

Designing comprehensive & structured training calendar. Behavioral & Technical training for line & staff.

#### Soft Skills/ Communication/Behavioral Trainings

Teaching interpersonal skills like communication, leadership and teamwork.

## **SKILLS**

Coaching & Mentoring

E-Learning, Blended & Digital Learning

#### **EDUCATION**

M.B.A (HR)

MIT-COE Pune University

2012 - 2014 62%

B.E (E&TC)

**MMCOE** Pune University

2007 - 2011 61%

## **COURSES**

HR Analytics & Digital HR Course Indian Institute of Management (IIM) Indore

Diploma in Design Thinking

Alison Certifications

Diploma in Neuro-linguistic Perspectives Alison Certifications

Instructional Design Principles to Create Successful E-Learning Courses

Alison Certificates

### **WORK HISTORY**

Finite4 Engineering Services (02/2022 - 08/2022) Talent Acquisition Executive

Persistent Systems (07/2021 - 01/2022)

Talent Acquisition Executive

PD's Academy (Founder & Lecturer) (02/2015 - Present)

L & D and Training facilitator

Hexagon Executive Search Firm (08/2014 - 02/2015)

Recruitment Consultant

PGA Edutech (01/2011 - 12/2012)

HR Executive